Emily McDaniel

Coaching Assistant

1234 Address San Diego, California, 92121 emcdaniel@ucsd.edu 888-888-8888

Energetic athletic coach who has been playing volleyball for 12+ years and knows the balance between athletics and academics. Currently playing Division 1 volleyball at UC San Diego in the Big West Conference. Highly reviewed by all parents as a dedicated, relentless, and reliable coach. Looking to mentor and motivate athletes while showing all the joy there is when playing volleyball.

Key Skills

- Time Management and Organization
- · Communication with all age levels
- · Leadership experience
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Problem Solving Skills

Professional Experience

Assistant Coach

DIME Volleyball Club | May 2022 - August 2022

- Assistant Coached the 12-2's team
- Taught basic fundamentals such as passing, setting, hitting, blocking, and serving
- Stated and scouted during tournaments
- Traveled to Las Vegas Qualifier and all SCVA tournaments
- Conducted warm-ups, drills, and games

Head Coach

NOC Volleyball Club | June 2020 - Present

- Ran the summer programs for both 8U-11 and 12-15 year olds
- Managed groups up to 25 players
- Motivated players through positive reinforcement while teaching new techniques
- Scheduled, planned, and conducted drills based on each group's skill level
- Ran elite 6v6 competitions for the advanced groups
- Created line-ups and scouted opposing teams

Assistant Coach

Canyon High School | June 2022 - August 2022

- · Worked as an assistant coach during the summer high school tryouts
- Performed demo's and taught basic fundamentals
- Helped create and refine the roster for each team

Education

Bachelor of Science in Public Health Medicine UC San Diego at La Jolla, CA | August 2021 - Present

Accomplishments

- All Big West Freshman Team (2021)
- Honorable Mention All Big West Team (2021)
- Canyon High School Leader of the Year Award (2021)
- Captain all 6 years of club volleyball (2015-2021)
- Canyon High School 2x MVP (2020-2021)